Year - Year of the March Madness game in question

Round - Game round in March Madness

Region - Region of the tournament in which the game takes place

Team1 - Name of first team in the march madness game

Seed1 - Seed of first team in the march madness game

Team2 - Name of second team in the march madness game

Seed2 - Seed of second team in the march madness game

Score - Score of the game in question

Winner - Winner of the game in question

Team1_Rk - National ranking of the first team during the year in question

Team1_Conf - Conference the first team plays in
 
Team1_W-L - Win/Loss record of the first team for the given season

Team1_NetRtg - Net Efficiency Rating of the first team, calculated by computing the difference between the offensive and defensive efficiency for the first team.

Team1_ORtg - Offensive Efficiency, calculated by averaging the points scored by the first team per 100 possessions in the average game

Team1_ORtg_RANK - The numeric ranking of the offensive efficiency for the first team out of all teams in a given season.

Team1_DRtg - Defensive efficiency, calculated by averaging the amount of points given up per 100 possessions.

Team1_DRtg_RANK - The numeric ranking of the defensive efficiency for the first team out of all teams in a given season.

Team1_AdjT - Adjusted tempo for the first team; the average amount of possessions the team has per 40 minutes (per game).

Team1_AdjT_RANK - The numeric ranking of the adjusted tempo of the first team when compared to all other teams in the given season.

Team1_Luck - Luck Ranking of the first team; calculated via the deviation of winning percentage of the teams actual schedule compared to the expected winning percentage. Positive figures represent good luck, while negative denotes bad luck.

Team1_Luck_RANK - Numeric ranking of the first teams luck rating when compared to all other teams in a given season.

Team1_Strength of Schedule NetRtg - Net Efficiency Rating for the first teams conference schedule; calculated by subtracting the in conference defensive efficiency rating from the in conference offensive efficiency rating.

Team1_Strength of Schedule NetRtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the first teams in conference net efficiency rating. This strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team1_Strength of Schedule ORtg - Net Offensive Efficiency Rating for the first teams in conference schedule; calculated by averaging the offensive efficiency of all teams in the first teams conference, excluding the team itself.

Team1_Strength of Schedule ORtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the first teams in conference offensive efficiency rating. This strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team1_Strength of Schedule DRtg - Net Defensive Efficiency Rating for the first teams in conference schedule; calculated by averaging the defensive efficiency of all teams in the first teams conference, excluding the team itself.

Team1_Strength of Schedule DRtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the first teams in conference defensive efficiency rating. This strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team1_NCSOS NetRtg - Non Conference Strength of Schedule Net Ranking � Calculated by averaging the net efficiency rating of all non-conference opponents for first team, in the given season.

Team1_NCSOS NetRtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the first teams non-conference net efficiency rating. This non-conference strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team1_Wins - The amount of games won by the first team in the given season.

Team1_Losses - The amount of games lost by the first team in the given season.

Team1_WinPct - Percentage of games won by the first team in a given season, calculated by dividing the number of games won in a season by the total number of games in the season.

Team2_Rk - National ranking of the second team during the year in question

Team2_Conf - Conference the second team plays in 

Team2_W-L - Win/Loss record of the second team for the given season

Team2_NetRtg - Net Efficiency Rating of the second team, calculated by computing the difference between the offensive and defensive efficiency for the second team.

Team2_ORtg - Offensive Efficiency, calculated by averaging the points scored by the second team per 100 possessions in the average game.

Team2_ORtg_RANK - The numeric ranking of the offensive efficiency for the second team out of all teams in a given season.

Team2_DRtg - Defensive efficiency, calculated by averaging the amount of points given up by the second team per 100 possessions.

Team2_DRtg_RANK - The numeric ranking of the defensive efficiency for the second team out of all teams in a given season.

Team2_AdjT - Adjusted tempo for the second team; the average amount of possessions the second team has per 40 minutes (per game).

Team2_AdjT_RANK - The numeric ranking of the adjusted tempo of the second team when compared to all other teams in the given season.

Team2_Luck - Luck Ranking of the second team; calculated via the deviation of winning percentage of the teams actual schedule compared to the expected winning percentage. Positive figures represent good luck, while negative denotes bad luck.

Team2_Luck_RANK - Numeric ranking of the second teams luck rating when compared to all other teams in a given season.

Team2_Strength of Schedule NetRtg - Net Efficiency Rating for the second teams conference schedule; calculated by subtracting the in conference defensive efficiency rating from the in conference offensive efficiency rating.

Team2_Strength of Schedule NetRtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the second teams in conference net efficiency rating. This strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team2_Strength of Schedule ORtg - Net Offensive Efficiency Rating for the second team�s in conference schedule; calculated by averaging the offensive efficiency of all teams in the second teams conference, excluding the team itself.

Team2_Strength of Schedule ORtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the second teams in conference offensive efficiency rating. This strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team2_Strength of Schedule DRtg - Net Defensive Efficiency Rating for the second teams in conference schedule; calculated by averaging the defensive efficiency of all teams in the second teams conference, excluding the team itself.

Team2_Strength of Schedule DRtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the second teams in conference defensive efficiency rating. This strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team2_NCSOS NetRtg - Non Conference Strength of Schedule Net Ranking - Calculated by averaging the net efficiency rating of all non-conference opponents for the second team, in the given season.

Team2_NCSOS NetRtg_RANK - Numeric ranking of the second teams non-conference net efficiency rating. This non-conference strength of schedule net rating is ranked nationally between all teams.

Team2_Wins - The amount of games won by the second team in the given season.

Team2_Losses - The amount of games lost by the second team in the given season.

Team2_WinPct - Percentage of games won by the second team in a given season, calculated by dividing the number of games won in a season by the total number of games in the season.

